Kayla Glick

Raleigh, NC (815) 757-0118 kaylaglick12@gmail.com kayla-glick.github.io

Skills & Knowledge

Programming Languages

Ruby, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, HTML, SCSS, Go

Libraries & Frameworks

Ruby on Rails, React, Twirp, Node.js, Bootstrap

Software Design Principles

System Design, Data Modeling, Project Management, REST & RPC APIs, UI/UX,

Other Tools

Git, Figma, Heroku, Kafka, Docker

Other Interests

Fantasy World-Building
PC & Tabletop Gaming
Architecture & Design
Music & Composition
Food & Cooking
Coffee

Summary

Detail-oriented senior software engineer with 8 years of experience leading and collaborating with teams to design, build, and deploy web applications at scale with a focus on UI/UX, performance, and observability. Seeking senior+ roles with opportunities to lead teams, design systems, and drive top-notch UI/UX.

Experience

GitHub

Senior Software Engineer

Aug 2022 - Present

Remote

- Act as tech lead and provide technical guidance for billing projects.
- Provide guidance for React and UI/UX initiatives both on billing and across GitHub.
- Build new tools and services using Ruby on Rails, Go, React, and TypeScript in both a monolith and multiple microservices.
- Model for both relational and non-relational data at enterprise scale on top of MySQL and Cosmos DB.
- Facilitate team retros and technical discussions to improve how the team works together socially and technically.
- Train and mentor others through pairing, discussions, and presentations.

Dutchie

Senior Software Engineer II Remote

Nov 2021 - Jul 2022

- One of the lead engineers for Dutchie's payments team.
- Architected the workflows, services, and underlying relational data models supporting Dutchie's in-house payments service, Dutchie Pay.
- Drafted engineering project blueprints from product specifications and design mock-ups, and consult on blueprints from other teams.
- Collaborated with product & design to produce high-level estimates to help determine project timelines and developer allocations.
- Drove incident response and managed releases and deployments for the payments team using Heroku Enterprise.
- Mentored and provided guidance to other members of the engineering org.

Senior Software Engineer I

Mar 2021 - Nov 2021

- Developed a new platform for accepting online credit card payments with

- Rails, GraphQL, and React.Devised new patterns to consolidate Dutchie's back-end service objects.
- Proposed improvements to Dutchie's testing practices.
- Began investigation and initial planning for Dutchie Pay.



Senior Web Developer

Jan 2020 - Feb 2021

Charleston, SC / Remote

- Collaborated with stakeholders to plan new features, sprints and releases.
- Led multiple projects to improve front-end UX, including implementing Bootstrap and re-designing multiple sections of our applications.
- Optimized back-end components to improve application performance.

Web Developer

Oct 2018 - Dec 2019

Remote

- Joined the same team I had interned for after graduation, performing many of the same responsibilities as I had previously.
- Interfaced with analysts to devise new requirements for and make improvements to our applications.

Intern Web Developer

Jun 2015 - Sep 2018

Charleston, SC

- Learned Ruby on Rails, HTML, JavaScript and other web development concepts from scratch while attending school.
- Collaborated with other interns and full-time developers to build and maintain full-stack Ruby on Rails web applications.

Education

College of Charleston, SC

2018

B.S. Computer Science Minor in Mathematics